<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Websocket on Pawan Chaurasia</title><link>/tags/websocket/</link><description>Recent content in Websocket on Pawan Chaurasia</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/websocket/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AIMING: First Time Right While Developing Software</title><link>/engineering/aiming_first_time_right/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/engineering/aiming_first_time_right/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Aiming for First Time Right&amp;rdquo; explores how planning, documentation, and rigorous testing can transform software development, sharing personal experiences from early startups to structured teams at LatitudePay.</description></item><item><title>Securing the websocket connection</title><link>/engineering/securing_websocket_connections/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/engineering/securing_websocket_connections/</guid><description>This blog extends our previous discussion on WebSockets with FastAPI. Sure, everything worked fine, but I conveniently skipped the most important part—security. Oops! Consider this my redemption post, where I’ll dive deep into securing WebSocket connections and, of course, sneak in some crude humor because why should security be boring?</description></item><item><title>WebSockets in FastAPI: From Basics to Scaling</title><link>/engineering/websocket_in_fast_api/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/engineering/websocket_in_fast_api/</guid><description>WebSockets enable real-time, bidirectional communication, perfect for chat apps, live notifications, and gaming. FastAPI, a modern Python framework, makes it easy to implement WebSockets for scalable, real-time applications. This blog walks you through setting up WebSocket connections, handling messages, and managing client-server interactions in FastAPI, with practical examples and best practices.</description></item></channel></rss>